<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-15T11:44:28+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Computational AEC Melbourne</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">24 September 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/event/2020/09/20/EventVI.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="24 September 2020" /><published>2020-09-20T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-09-20T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/event/2020/09/20/EventVI</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/event/2020/09/20/EventVI.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Thursday, 24 September 2020&lt;/code&gt;
6:00 pm – 7:30 pm AEST&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Swinburne University Online Classroom&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Meeting Link: will be emailed to registrants 48 hours prior to meeting kick-off&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;robotic-fabrication-in-aec&quot;&gt;Robotic Fabrication in AEC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Speakers&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dr-dagmar-reinhardt-the-university-of-sydney-a-professor-chair-of-architecture&quot;&gt;Dr. Dagmar Reinhardt, The University of Sydney (A. Professor, Chair of Architecture)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;robotics-in-architecture-human-robot-collaboration-and-industry-40&quot;&gt;Robotics in architecture, Human-robot collaboration and Industry 4.0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Dagmar Reinhardt is a practising architect, researcher and educator. Reinhardt leads the robotics research group and the Master of Digital Architecture Research stream and at the School of Architecture, Design and Planning, The University of Sydney, and her design research studios are regularly awarded the prestigious National Student Award for Structural Innovation and for Digital Innovation by the AIA Institute of Architects, Sydney, NSW. Lecturing internationally, she was the Foundational Program Director of the Bachelor of Architecture and Environments (BAE, 2014-2018). As a practising architect, her built works, competitions and installations are research-based, widely published and have received numerous recognitions and awards for affordable and multi-generational residential works (www.reinhardtjung.de).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reinhardt’s research focuses on the intersection and integration of architecture, acoustics, structure, robotics, fabrication, material and constructions constraints into design and interdisciplinary collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;daniel-prohasky-swinburne-university-lecturer-in-architectural-engineering&quot;&gt;Daniel Prohasky, Swinburne University (Lecturer in Architectural Engineering)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;curvecrete&quot;&gt;Curvecrete&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Prohasky is an architectural engineer and roboticist passionate about translating research towards industry adoption in Australia, particularly in the building design and construction industry. He is the founding lecturer in Architectural Engineering at Swinburne University and was Swinburne’s 2019 Design Faculty Innovation Fellow to further develop an innovative advanced manufacturing venture, Curvecrete. Curvecrete technology was proudly invented at the University of Melbourne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, Daniel will address some of the key challenges around navigating the balance between architecture and engineering, academia and research commercialisation, and how we might disrupt the industry as we know it through computational design of virtual and physical systems aka advanced manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alexander-nikolas-walzer--rmit-university-research-fellow&quot;&gt;Alexander Nikolas Walzer , RMIT University (Research Fellow)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;applying-lean-production-methods-to-construction&quot;&gt;Applying lean production methods to construction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex is a Melbourne-based researcher exploring tech in AEC. Currently, he is part of the RMIT x IMCRC Design Robotics developing new workflows for Australian SMEs. Prior to this role, he was an assistant at ETH Zurich and the NCCR Digital Fabrication. Alex has consulted several companies and organizations on the possibilities of the ongoing digitization in AEC. On the weekend, he is a passionate Maker and Motorcyclist and loves a good IPA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will highlight a few case studies, the importance of collaboration, economies of scale, as well as opportunities, challenges and incentives for new and existing firms to embrace digital fabrication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;followed-by&quot;&gt;Followed by:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual drinks and networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;register-here-httpswwweventbritecomauecomputational-aec-september-2020&quot;&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com.au/e/computational-aec-september-2020-tickets-119875052509&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com.au/e/computational-aec-september-2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Thursday, 24 September 2020 6:00 pm – 7:30 pm AEST</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MSD at HOME with P. BLOCK, J. BURRY and R. SNOOKS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/07/06/MSDatHome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MSD at HOME with P. BLOCK, J. BURRY and R. SNOOKS" /><published>2020-07-06T16:39:30+10:00</published><updated>2020-07-06T16:39:30+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2020/07/06/MSDatHome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/07/06/MSDatHome.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;digital-fabrication-post-covid-19-rethinking-construction-techniques-or-business-as-usual&quot;&gt;Digital fabrication post-COVID-19: rethinking construction techniques or business-as-usual&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;philippe-block-jane-burry-roland-snooks-and-paul-loh&quot;&gt;Philippe BLOCK, Jane BURRY, Roland SNOOKS and Paul LOH&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/McBquNxnbqc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Digital fabrication post-COVID-19: rethinking construction techniques or business-as-usual Philippe BLOCK, Jane BURRY, Roland SNOOKS and Paul LOH</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Parametric-Architecture Interviews</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/30/ParametricInterviews.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Parametric-Architecture Interviews" /><published>2020-06-30T16:39:30+10:00</published><updated>2020-06-30T16:39:30+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/30/ParametricInterviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/30/ParametricInterviews.html">&lt;p&gt;A series of talks and interviews with prominent Architects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 018 – Moshe Safdie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 017 – Kim Herthforth Nielsen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 016 – Hernan Diaz Alonso&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 015 – Kengo Kuma&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 014 – Melike Altinisik&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 013 – Mario Carpo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 012 – Hanif Kara&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 011 – James Von Klemperer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 010 – Michel Rojkind&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 009 – Fernando Romero&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 008 – Peter Eisenman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 007 – Ma Yansong&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 006 – Richard Hassell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 005 – Stefan Antoni&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 004 – Patrik Schumacher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 003 – Cyril Lancelin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 002 – Sanjay Puri&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Live 001 – Refik Anadol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Talks 006 - Alireza Taghaboni&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Talks 005 - Chris Precht&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Talks 004 - Habibeh Madjdabadi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Talks 003 - Ferda Kolatan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Talks 002 - Mario Carpo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PA Talks 001 - Han Tumertekin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://parametric-architecture.com/interviews/&quot;&gt;parametric-architecture.com/interviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A series of talks and interviews with prominent Architects:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Organic Towns From Square Tiles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/29/StalbergTalk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organic Towns From Square Tiles" /><published>2020-06-29T16:39:30+10:00</published><updated>2020-06-29T16:39:30+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/29/StalbergTalk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/29/StalbergTalk.html">&lt;p&gt;Organic Towns From Square Tiles - a talk by OSKAR STÅLBERG at INDIECADE EUROPE 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1hqt8JkYRdI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Organic Towns From Square Tiles - a talk by OSKAR STÅLBERG at INDIECADE EUROPE 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IFC OpenBIM SVG construction documentation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/20/IFCSVG.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IFC OpenBIM SVG construction documentation" /><published>2020-06-20T16:39:30+10:00</published><updated>2020-06-20T16:39:30+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/20/IFCSVG</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/20/IFCSVG.html">&lt;p&gt;IFC OpenBIM SVG construction documentation - 200620 BlenderBIM Add-on Technical WIP Demo by dion Moult&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peertube.social/videos/watch/021a6574-b175-4c43-b83d-6a133c54a199&quot;&gt;Watch the Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">IFC OpenBIM SVG construction documentation - 200620 BlenderBIM Add-on Technical WIP Demo by dion Moult</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From Here; For Now. MSD at HOME</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/17/MSDatHome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Here; For Now. MSD at HOME" /><published>2020-06-17T16:39:30+10:00</published><updated>2020-06-17T16:39:30+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/17/MSDatHome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/06/17/MSDatHome.html">&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://msd.unimelb.edu.au/events/msd-at-home/from-here-for-now&quot;&gt;msd.unimelb.edu.au/events/msd-at-home/from-here-for-now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Here; For Now is an online talk series curated by Colby Vexler, Anna Tonkin, Eric Ye, and Guillermo Fernández-Abascal, with Justin Clemens and Alan Pert, and design by Nicole Ho and Samson Ossedryver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCDUvpSzYkKEfmdfG7FTIMiQ&quot;&gt;Link to YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Source: msd.unimelb.edu.au/events/msd-at-home/from-here-for-now</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">25 June 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/event/2020/06/15/EventV.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="25 June 2020" /><published>2020-06-15T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-06-15T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/event/2020/06/15/EventV</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/event/2020/06/15/EventV.html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5pSdmY-9lVI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Thursday, 25 June 2020&lt;/code&gt;
6:00 pm – 7:30 pm AEST&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Swinburne University Online Classroom&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Meeting Link: will be emailed to registrants 48 hours prior to meeting kick-off&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;xr-vrarmr-in-aec&quot;&gt;XR (VR/AR/MR) in AEC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Speakers&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gwyllim-jahn-fologram-holographic-construction-with-fologram-immediate-opportunities-and-use-cases-for-mixed-reality-in-aec&quot;&gt;Gwyllim Jahn, Fologram: Holographic Construction with Fologram. Immediate opportunities and use cases for mixed reality in AEC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwyllim Jahn is the co-founder and creative director of Fologram, a Melbourne-based startup building mixed reality software solutions for architecture, engineering and construction. Fologram’s software overlays physical environments with precise, interactive digital models that can be used for rapid prototyping of mixed reality applications to solve design and construction challenges. Gwyllim will share how Fologram’s clients and partners have identified high value use cases and immediate opportunities for mixed reality to reduce construction time, cost and risk through several recently completed case study projects. These include work by All Brick to replace traditional 2D drawings with interactive, shared and in-situ holographic models describing all construction stages of the brickwork in the Royal Hobart Hospital, and the effective use of analogue tools and traditional steam-bending techniques to fabricate the complex double-curved structure of the Tallinn Architecture Biennial pavilion.
Rhino users in the audience are encouraged to download and install the Fologram for Rhino plugin and the Fologram for Mobile app in order to participate in a brief tutorial at the conclusion of the presentation illustrating how to stream models from Rhino and Grasshopper to mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get Fologram: www.fologram.com/download&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fologram for Mobile - Search on the App Store or Google Play&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/fologram/9nn9sjwh9qc1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fologram for HoloLens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, case study projects and examples see: 
www.fologram.com
vimeo.com/fologram
instagram.com/fologm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;johan-hanegraaf-arkio-collaborative-spatial-design&quot;&gt;Johan Hanegraaf, Arkio: Collaborative spatial design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technologies like BIM enhancedour industriesability to collaborate however architects need training and discipline before they can harness tools like Revit during the earlydesign stages. Designers often fall back on exploring ideas usingtraditional sketches, scale models and screen-based 3D modeling tools that can be time consuming to create and difficult to communicate.Arkio is a collaborative VR/AR design tool that makes creating and validating spatial ideas more engaging for everyone. During this talk we will introduce and give a live demonstration of Arkio to show how it can be used to quickly sketch out various design proposalstogether on different devices. We will show how data from Excel, Rhino and Revit can be used in a virtual design session and howthe design outcomes can be loaded back into native Revit families and masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With ten years experience in the Architecture field implementing and developing design tools for Mecanoo’s computational projects, Johan’s early exploration of immersive technology led him to join Arkio, a startup creating a unique collaborative VR/AR design tool. As an engineer and architect by education, he strongly believes that our computational tools should be moreintuitive and collaborative if we want them to enhance creativity and support a better built environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;michael-gardiner-unsigned-studio-vr-application-on-major-engineering-projects&quot;&gt;Michael Gardiner, Unsigned Studio: VR application on major engineering projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, Michael will take us through case studies that demonstrate the use of virtual reality on major engineering projects. We will start with the client problem, and move onto the VR-based solution through an explanation of the decision making process and the reasoning behind. In addition to the technical solution, Michael will touch on commercial considerations when deploying VR across major projects, lessons learnt and a thought on future applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Gardiner is the Brisbane Studio Leader for Unsigned Studio, Aurecon’s internal creative visualisation and technology group. Michael has over 15 years’ experience delivering visualisation and managing global strategy, and specialises in facilitating the connections between visual technologies and the decision-making process.
Michael works with a range of real-time software to explore visualisation as it relates to design, engagement, experience and operations. He is dedicated to evolving the role of visualisation into core design thinking by increasing its application across the entire project lifecycle. Combining these ideas with strategic global implementation of emerging technologies such as Virtual and Augmented Reality ensures that Aurecon is positioned to meet our client’s visual needs now and into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alex-coulombe-agile-lens-5-ways-xr-makes-you-a-better-architect&quot;&gt;Alex Coulombe, Agile Lens: 5 Ways XR Makes You a Better Architect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, Alex Coulombe of Agile Lens distills key lessons based on over tenyears of working with immersive technology. Case studies will be shown of projects at every phase of the design process where VR and/or AR became uniquely suited to solve a difficult problem. Whether you’ve been using turnkey XR solutions for years, or are still skeptical thatthere would ever be any reason to put on a headset, by the end of this talk you’ll be inspired to dive intoutilizing these tools in entirely new ways&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architect turned XR-chitect, Alex Coulombe is a designer, developer, and educator who has worked in VR/AR for over 10 years. After earning his B.Arch. from Syracuse University, Alex practiced at such firms as Rafael Viñoly Architectsand Zimmer Gunsul Frasca Architects, always advocating for the utilization of emerging technologies to communicate design intent. After developing at Fisher Dachs Associates the world’s first virtual reality system for evaluating theatre sightlines, he co-founded the NYC-based studio, Agile Lens. Projects have included The Shed, David Geffen Hall, The Statue of Liberty Museum, Rice University Music and Performing Arts Center, and the dome of the Ed Sullivan Theatre for The Late Show with Stephen Colbert. Two years of recent study in social VR live performance with the group Alive in Plasticland led to a scripted piece, “Loveseat,” being selected for the 2019 Venice Film Festival. Alex designedthe virtual set, props, lighting, and even the theatre architecture in which the performances were viewed by audience members in Venice and around the world(via VR). Alex also co-created the award-winning Magic Leap ghost speed-dating experience, “Ghosted,” sits on the advisory board for AIXR’s Enterprise committee, has created several courses for Unreal Engine, and actively teaches Unity at Syracuse University. A rising thought leader in emerging tech, Alex speaks at conferences around the world. Follow him on Twitter and YouTube: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ibrews?lang=en&quot;&gt;@ibrews&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;followed-by&quot;&gt;Followed by:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual drinks and networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;register-here-httpswwweventbritecomauecomputational-aec-june-2020&quot;&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com.au/e/computational-aec-june-2020-tickets-108515113626&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com.au/e/computational-aec-june-2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">pyRevit Routes (HTTP API)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/04/30/pyRevitRoutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="pyRevit Routes (HTTP API)" /><published>2020-04-30T16:39:30+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T16:39:30+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2020/04/30/pyRevitRoutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/04/30/pyRevitRoutes.html">&lt;p&gt;Control Revit from a web application&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so/pyRevit-Routes-HTTP-API-79ef6d4a77b04aca9be6f4e46ffa728e&quot;&gt;pyRevit-Routes-HTTP-API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say we want to create a web application that would display a list of doors in a model. The web application would be split into two parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Font-end&lt;/strong&gt;: the part that runs in the browser and acts as the user interface, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back-end&lt;/strong&gt;: the part that the front-end contacts to send and receive data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you are free to select whatever toolchain and GUI framework (React, Vue.js, etc) you are comfortable with for the front-end, the challenge has always been on how to create a back-end that has access to Revit contexts and can query or modify Revit documents. What we really needed is to run a HTTP web server over a running Revit instance and manage the HTTP calls in a way that would be executed in Revit context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;strong&gt;Routes&lt;/strong&gt; python module, is an HTTP micro-framework to create web APIs running over Revit instances. This means that you can create functionality that could be triggerd from remote. This framework provides the necessary mechanism to create a back-end that has access to Revit context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rUCM0pJz5Zw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also worth looking at Radu Gidei’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/radumg/DynaServer&quot;&gt;DynaServer&lt;/a&gt; implemented for Dynamo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Control Revit from a web application</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Build a Swarm App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/04/22/SwarmApp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Build a Swarm App" /><published>2020-04-22T16:39:30+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-22T16:39:30+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2020/04/22/SwarmApp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/04/22/SwarmApp.html">&lt;p&gt;Swarm is an app store for the design community. It connects Designers who need tools with the Superusers who are building them.  Swarm allows design teams to discover and share solutions that empower creatives to do their best work.
More info here &lt;a href=&quot;http://core.thorntontomasetti.com/announcing-swarm/&quot;&gt;core.thorntontomasetti.com/announcing-swarm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to Build a Swarm App&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/56qk4eRPiDQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building and Editing Swarm Apps: Part 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2qYyYhZgc1s&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building and Editing Swarm Apps: Part 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oOL3_bm3-Bg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Swarm is an app store for the design community. It connects Designers who need tools with the Superusers who are building them. Swarm allows design teams to discover and share solutions that empower creatives to do their best work. More info here core.thorntontomasetti.com/announcing-swarm</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Books for free from Springer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/04/20/Springer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Books for free from Springer" /><published>2020-04-20T16:39:30+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-20T16:39:30+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/2020/04/20/Springer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/2020/04/20/Springer.html">&lt;p&gt;Python, R, Data Science, and other science &amp;amp; engineering books available for free from Springer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Springer, the famous European scientific publisher, has announced they are making several hundred technical books available for free download, due to the current situation.  There are many computer science, math, and engineering books, as well as some Python books&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/search?facet-series=%227592%22&amp;amp;facet-content-type=%22Book%22&amp;amp;showAll=false&quot;&gt;SpringerLink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Python, R, Data Science, and other science &amp;amp; engineering books available for free from Springer.</summary></entry></feed>